Raheem Abdullahi Abiodun

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

raheemabiodun23@gmail.com | GitHub | Linkedin | Twitter | Portfolio |

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer, and open-source enthusiast with love for clean code and accessible design. Passionate in test driven development, pair-programming, and remote work. An outstanding teacher, with vast experience in teaching, tailored to include all learning styles, to aid better understanding, with multiple awards to show for my excellent work. Fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of ramping up quickly and efficiently.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, Webpack, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MySQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev

Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Collaborative work, Mentoring and Code

Review.

EXPERIENCE

MICROVERSE Remote
Code Reviewer May 2022 - Present

- Reviewed code for more than 450 junior web developers, providing technical support, and advice on how to write clean code and accessible design through code reviews.
- Reviewed technical and soft skills which are fundamental to growth and progress.
- Provided advice on improving social media presence, and networking with fellow developers across the world.

Mentor (Volunteer)

April 2022 - Present

- Mentored 4 junior web developers, who went on to build outstanding projects with good recommendations.
- Proposed improvements to code organization, to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program, which drove junior developers to complete their programs.

De Revelation College 15, Funmilayo Adiele Street, Aparadija, Ogun State, Nigeria Mathematics and Chemistry Teacher January 2020 - December 2021

- Taught about 980 students mathematics and chemistry, with 100% of the final year students having distinctions in mathematics and chemistry in their final exams.
- Organized inter-class, and inter-school debates for students to improve their communication skills, which saw De Revelation College coming first positions on multiple occasions.

TREGS 12, Adeleke Close, Darfur Iyana - Ota, Ogun State, Nigeria Mathematics and Chemistry Teacher September 2018 - December 2020

- Taught about 760 students mathematics and chemistry, with 100% of the final year students having distinctions in mathematics and chemistry in their final exams.
- Guided the students during practical classes, performing several experiments and analyses, which heathens their understanding of chemistry and mathematics.

FHI360 Data entry/Data analysis

2B Sabo Bakin Zuwo Road, Kano State, Nigeria July 2017 - November 2018

- Collated data of about 15,000 HIV clients receiving treatment in Kano state, Nigeria, between 2010 - 2017 using LAMIS.
- Collated data of over 12,000 vulnerable children receiving treatment from 5 different hospitals in Kano state, Nigeria, between 2005 2017 using NOMIS software.
- Analyzed all the data collated with my team, to ascertain clients who are still receiving treatment, dead, or lost to follow-up.

EMPOWER MONITORING TEAM Empower Collation Officer

10A, Wuse, Abuja, Nigeria December 2017 - March 2018

- Lead a team to verify the data of about 15,470 Federal government poverty alleviation scheme(Empower) beneficiaries, Kano State chapter.
- Collation of the data verified for proper documentation.

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full-stack Web Developer

February 2022- Present

<u>Budget App</u> — Budget app is a Ruby on Rails application that keeps track of expenses. To use this app, you will have to create an account and log into your account.

<u>Book Store</u> — Book Store is a single page application that allow users to keep track of books coming into the store, and books leaving the store. This project was built with react and redux.

<u>Built a movie page</u> — This project allows the user to view the latest movies and leave comments and a like.

<u>Portfolio project</u> — This Project allows web newbies to get started with web development online. Built with: (VsCode, HTML, CSS and JavaScript(DOM)).

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

February 2022 - Present

Remote full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with other developers.

LADOKE AKINTOLA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

Bachelor of Technology in Chemical Engineering

September 2010 - December 2015

- Introduction to flowsheeting and Aspen Hysis.
- Introduction to Armod modeling software to study the rate and amount of pollutants dispersed across Nigeria.